Lee Chenalloy

Phone: 908-420-5419 | Email: lchenalloy@gmail.com | Edison, NJ 08817 LinkedIn: https://bit.ly/chenalleegit | Github: https://bit.ly/chenalleegit

Portfolio: https://chenallee.now.sh/

Summary

Front end Developer, design enthusiast, and IT graduate. Brings a history with developing projects from educational experience along with excellent client and team communication skills from retail roles. Recognized as a quick learner and diligent team member for organizational and communication skills.

Technical Skills

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, CSS Grid, Media Queries, JavaScript, ES6, jQuery, Node.Js, Express, APIs, JSON, Rest, AJAX, GIT, Github, the command line, MySQL, Sequelize, Jest, Java, C#, Excel, React, Chakra UI

Education

Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey, New Brunswick, NJ - 2020

Certificate - Full Stack Web Development

Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey, New Brunswick, NJ - 2017

Bachelor of Arts - Information Technology and Informatics: Game Production and Innovation / Japanese

Projects

Singalong App - https://github.com/chenallee/Lyryx-Webplayer | https://github.com/chenallee/Lyryx-Webplayer | https://github.io/Concatenated-Cats/

- An app that uses the Spotify API and Web Playback SDK as well as the Lyrics.OVH API to allow authenticated users to view the lyrics of the currently playing track. Deployed on Github.
- Lead developer of a group of three, communicated project plans and wrote most of the JavaScript.

Watchlist API Endpoints - https://github.com/chenallee/Watchlist-API

- Leverages Restful API endpoints and Sequelize to interact with a MySQL Database in which authenticated users can store shows on their watch lists on an Express Server made through Node.js.
- Lead developer of a group of three, provided guidance and debugging, and wrote a thorough readme detailing how to test the endpoints in Insomnia.

Watchlzts App - https://watchlzts.herokuapp.com/ | https://github.com/chenallee/Watchlzts

- A full stack MERN app that allows authenticated users to track their watch status of seasons and full television shows. Uses React hooks and state management with Chakra UI on the front end, Mongo for the back end, and JSON Web Tokens for authentication. Deployed on Heroku.
- Solo project, carried concept from the first iteration through completion, taught self new technologies during development.

Experience

TD Bank - Teller II | 09/2017 - 2020

• Recognized by management for commitment to teamwork in communicating with the team regarding store upkeep and operational procedures to ensure efficient processes.

Shoprite - Cashier | 06/2017 - 11/2017

 Received several awards for being singled out by customers for exceptional care and customer service.

Little Sheep Mongolian Hot Pot - Host | 05/2014 - 08/2014

 Served as principal host during the first few months of opening, playing an integral role of training subsequent hosts and upholding the brand image.